adconductor.com 2014-12-15

# Privacy | AdConductor

## Privacy Statement

### Effective date: March 21, 2014

Fundamentally, the privacy of web users must be protected and the most effective way to preserve that privacy is to confine their data to the site level. Burst Media as well as adConductor collect no personally identifiable data, and therefore, protect user privacy. Burst’s TRUSTe license verifies this privacy stance.

This privacy policy applies to http://www.burstmedia.com, http://ads.addesktop.com, http://www.burstnet.com and http://www.AdConductor.com owned and operated by Burst Media Corporation (“Burst Media” or “Burst”). This privacy policy describes how Burst Media collects and uses the personal information you provide on our web sites:  http://www.burstmedia.com, http://ads.addesktop.com, http://www.burstnet.com and [http://www.AdConductor.com](http://www.adconductor.com/).

It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

Internet user privacy and confidentiality is of the utmost importance to Burst, our web publisher members, and our advertiser clients. Our reputation and integrity are directly related to how we serve our clients and customers. Please find a description below of how Burst strives to protect the privacy of Internet users and maintain the Internet as a highly credible medium.

### Data Collection of User Information

All users who receive an ad served by Burst retain complete anonymity where Burst is concerned. As ads are delivered, Burst does not acquire or collect any personal information about you. Your name, address, phone number, and email address all remain your private property. Burst does, however, collect information that is specific to how you use the Internet. This non-personally identifying information can include, and is not limited to, the server you are logged onto, the geographic location of the ISP you use, the type of browser you use, and your IP address. This information is obtained solely for the purpose of targeting ads and measuring a given ad’s effectiveness on behalf of Burst clients and customers.

There are instances where a user may provide specific personal information in response to an ad containing a survey, purchase agreement, or registration questionnaire. For such programs, Burst (or a third party working in conjunction with Burst and the advertiser) acquires this information on behalf of the advertiser client. The client uses this information to deliver the goods or services requested by the user. When requested, Burst may employ this information in a compiled format without identifying users specifically to provide to the advertiser client precise profiles of the types of individuals responding to the ads.

### PRIVACY

Burst Media is a member of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) and is in compliance with the NAI’s Self-Regulatory Principles, and adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising.

### USE OF HEALTH RELATED INFORMATION

Burst is a member of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) and adheres to its Code on Health-Related Data. Burst Media does not collect or use “sensitive consumer information” (as defined in the NAI’s Self-Regulatory Code of Conduct) in its online behavioral advertising activities and does not offer or sell to its clients segments based on sensitive consumer information. “Sensitive consumer information” includes social security numbers or other government-issued identifiers, insurance plan numbers, financial account numbers, information that describes the precise real-time geographic location of an individual derived through location-based services such as through GPS-enabled devices, and precise information about past, present, or potential future health or medical conditions or treatments, including genetic, genomic and family medical history. Burst Media maintains internal policies and procedures designed to safeguard against the collection or use of such information.

Burst may use general health related information with customized advertising campaigns. General health-related information that is not based on a precise medical treatment or conditions is not considered “sensitive consumer information.” This information can include, but is not limited to the following examples: retargeting based on previous visit to an advertiser’s website, retargeting based upon the visit to a general health/fitness/wellness/nutrition website, or retargeting based on the visit to a website where interest can be inferred from common content e.g., pregnancy can be inferred from a visit to a infant car-seat review page.

### P3P

The Platform for Privacy Preferences (P3P) provides a way for Ad Networks and websites to publish their privacy policies in a machine-readable syntax. An Ad Network or website will deploy P3P in order to make its privacy practices more accessible to the site’s visitors. A visitor’s Web browser can download the machine-readable privacy statements, and compare the contents of those statements to the user’s preferences. This way, the user’s browser can automatically notify the user when they visit a site whose practices match the user’s preferences or warn the user if the practices and preferences don’t match. Burst Media has incorporated this technology in its ad servers. Our syntax reflects our current privacy policy.

### The Cookie Principle

Burst may use cookies to improve your Web browsing experience. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on your computer for the purpose of identifying your web browser. When you are served a Burst ad, Burst may assign in a cookie various information on ads you’ve seen, information on sites you’ve visited and activities performed to your computer browser. We do this to understand the way a user responds to the ads we deliver. For example, this information lets us keep track of how many times you view an ad we distribute. Likewise, the cookie can help make sure you do not see the same ad over and over – thus enhancing your online Web viewing experience.

Burst Media collects this information via our technology and it may be stored for up to 2 years for the purpose of: 1) analyzing campaign results, 2) ensuring that our technology is functioning properly, and 3) preventing fraud across our sites.

We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site or our member sites. We may obtain anonymous information about you – such as sites you have visited or products you have researched – from third-party sources, and combine it with data that we have collected to better target advertising that match your interests. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent that use if you desire.

In an effort to respect your privacy, Burst Media gives all internet users the choice to opt-out of receiving Burst Media cookies. If you would like to opt out, please visit our Cookie Opt-out Program at www.burstmedia.com/company/opt-out. Alternatively, you may also choose to opt out of receiving Burst Media cookies through the Network Advertising Initiative’s [Consumer Opt-Out Program](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

### Third-Party Measurement Services

Often, advertisers will employ a third-party service provider other than Burst for serving the advertisements and for tracking the performance of an ad program. These companies may employ cookie and 1×1 pixel technology to measure and improve the effectiveness of ads for their client. These companies may collect and use anonymous information about your visits to our member websites and other websites. The information collected can include:

  1. Date/time of your visit
  2. The banner ad that was shown
  3. Unique user ID
  4. Your IP address
  5. The URLs of sites you visit

This information can also be used for online preference marketing (“profiling”) purposes. In these instances, Burst has no control over the information collected by the third-party, and may not be held responsible for the actions of the third-party measurement service where collected information is concerned.

If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [ click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

### The Cookie Principle

adConductor may use cookies to improve your Web browsing experience. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on your computer for the purpose of identifying your web browser. When you are served an adConductor ad, adConductor may assign in a cookie various information on ads you’ve seen, information on sites you’ve visited and activities performed to your computer browser. We do this to understand the way a user responds to the ads we deliver. For example, this information lets us keep track of how many times you view an ad we distribute. Likewise, the cookie can help make sure you do not see the same ad over and over – thus enhancing your online Web viewing experience.

adConductor collects this information via our technology and it may be stored for up to 2 years for the purpose of: 1) analyzing campaign results, 2) ensuring that our technology is functioning properly, and 3) preventing fraud across our sites.

We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site or our member sites. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent that use if you desire.

### FOR PUBLISHERS WHO ARE MEMEBERS OF Burst OR ADCONDUCTOR CLIENTS:

This confirms that Burst Media is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. Burst Media also complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Burst Media has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Burst Media’s certification, please visit <http://export.gov/safeharbor/>.

For Burst Publishers the privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for www.Burstmedia.com and [www.Burstnet.com](http://www.burstnet.com/).

For AdConductor Customers this privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for [www.adConductor.com](http://www.adconductor.com/) and ads.adConductor.com.

Burst Media has been awarded TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe’s program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe’s mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at privacy@Burstmedia.com. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe by clicking here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

### Third-Party Measurement Services

Often, advertisers will employ a third-party service provider other than Burst for serving the advertisements and for tracking the performance of an ad program. These companies may employ cookie and 1×1 pixel technology to measure and improve the effectiveness of ads for their client. These companies may collect and use anonymous information about your visits to our member websites and other websites. The information collected can include:

  1. Date/time of your visit
  2. The banner ad that was shown
  3. Unique user ID
  4. Your IP address
  5. The URLs of sites you visit

This information can also be used for online preference marketing (“profiling”) purposes. In these instances, Burst has no control over the information collected by the third-party, and may not be held responsible for the actions of the third-party measurement service where collected information is concerned.

The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers use session ID and persistent cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site.

If you are a **Burst Publisher** and have questions regarding different third-party measurement services and their respective methods of information collection, please contact [privacy@Burstmedia.com](mailto:privacy@Burstmedia.com).

If you are an **adConductor Customer** and have questions regarding different third-party measurement services and their respective methods of information collection, please contact [privacy@adConductor.com](mailto:privacy@adConductor.com).

We do not share, sell, rent or trade PII with third-parties for promotional purposes:

### Personal Information

We collect information which is provided to us such as name, email and phone number on our site in the “Contact Us” section. This information is used to establish contact with perspective publishers and is only used for that purpose.

Burst regards all personal information collected from **Burst Publisher** as completely confidential. This includes personal data provided during registration processes and financial account information. Burst does offer to advertisers any data which may facilitate the sale of advertising for a member site. This includes traffic data, click-thru rates, unique visitor information, website geographic location, content information, and any demographic information offered by the website member for the purpose of facilitating an advertising sale.

Burst regards all personal information collected from its **AdConductor Customers** as completely confidential. This includes personal data provided during registration processes and financial account information.

### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as Tax ID number and/or social security number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). To learn more about SSL, follow this [link](http://www.thawte.com/resources/getting-started/how-ssl-works/index.html).

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. We use reasonable security to protect your personal information; we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our website, you can email us at [security@Burstmedia.com](mailto:security@Burstmedia.com).

### Disclosure

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

Burst openly volunteers its practices of collecting information, its targeting capabilities, and its use of cookies. If you are a **Burst Publisher** and have any questions pertaining to this privacy policy and its contents, please direct your correspondence to [privacy@Burstmedia.com](mailto:privacy@Burstmedia.com).

If you are an **adConductor Customer** and have any questions pertaining to this privacy policy and its contents, please direct your correspondence to [privacy@adConductor.com](mailto:privacy@adConductor.com).

### Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information

If a user’s personally identifiable information changes, (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users’ personally identifiable information. This can be done by logging into your user account and updating your personal information or discontinuing service at anytime. Burst Publishers can direct their request to [privacy@Burstmedia.com](mailto:privacy@Burstmedia.com) and we will change the information, as requested within 30 days.

**AdConductor Customers** can direct their request to [privacy@adConductor.com](mailto:privacy@adConductor.com) and we will change the information, as requested within 30 days.

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with an appropriate law enforcement investigation, current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Ad servers or website.

If Burst is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

### DATA RETENTION

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [privacy@adConductor.com](mailto:privacy@adConductor.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements

### Customer Testimonials

We post customer testimonials on our website which may contain personally identifiable information such as the customer’s name. We do obtain the customer’s consent prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial.

### Emails

Service-related Announcements

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, or a new account enhancement is released, which will affect the way you work with us, we might send you an email.

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account. You can deactivate your account by contacting Publisher Services and requesting that your account be closed. You can reach publisher services by email: [support@Burstmedia.com](mailto:support@Burstmedia.com) or by phone: 800-876-4352 or 781-852-5293.

Customer Service

Based upon the personally identifiable information that you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email with your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries to provide the services you request and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by email or telephone, in accordance with your wishes.

Choice/Opt-out

We do send out regular updates of recently added campaigns to **Burst Publishers**. If you no longer wish to receive those email updates, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each update or communication, by emailing us at [support@Burstmedia.com](mailto:support@Burstmedia.com) or by calling us at: 800-876-4352 or 781-852-5293.

Burst does not currently share personally identifiable information with third parties. Your information is only used to provide service and support while you work with Burst Media. Should that policy change, you will be notified when your personal information is collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider, so that you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.

### Bulletin Boards/Chat Rooms/Blogs

If you use a bulletin board or chat room on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

This website contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Burst Media. Please be aware that we, Burst Media, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information.

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this website.

### Social Media Features

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as Facebook and Twitter. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Notifications of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post these changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. Regardless of later updates, we will never use the information you submit under this current policy in a new way without first providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prevent that use. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.

**Burst Media**

8 New England Executive Park

Burlington, MA 01803
